Hey everybody, welcome to this A1
English listening practice video. Why is
this A1? Well, it's A1 because I am
going to talk slowly and use simpler
language than you would normally hear in
other videos.
But just know that some words and
phrases that I use will be new for you
or hard to understand for you. In my
opinion, the goal of an A1 listening
practice video is to help you get to an
A2 level.
It's not meant to keep you at A1. So, in
this A1 listening practice video, I'll
probably use words and phrases that are
a little bit of a higher level. um
because this is going to help you get
accustomed to more difficult English
because remember the goal with a
practice video for A1 English learners
is to help them reach the next level A2.
So, yes, I'm going to use language and
phrases that aren't technically A1, but
that doesn't matter. This is good
exposure for you to become exposed to
harder language so you can reach the
next level in your listening
comprehension. And of course, I can also
talk about more interesting things if I
can use language that's a little bit
challenging for an A1 learner. So, it
keeps the videos interesting as well.
So, uh today's topic is a little bit
different from normal. Uh recently I've
done a lot of videos about language
learning. Um, today's video is still
somewhat related to language learning,
but not quite, not exactly. I'm going to
talk about my international family.
This is an interesting topic for me and
I'm sure many of you will want to know a
little bit about my family and uh the
international
uh aspect of my family. So uh that's
what I'm going to talk about today in a
slow and clear way so you can practice
your listening. Before we continue, I
want to mention that if you want my
listening training to help you
understand native speakers better when
they speak fast, uh, and if you want my
pronunciation training so you can speak
and pronounce things more like a native
speaker, then make sure to check out my
membership because I offer a lot of
training and I help you become more uh
comfortable with understanding and
pronouncing
uh the sounds of English. So that link
is down below in the description. So let
me talk about my international family.
Now, my wife is from Mexico, from
Guadalajara, Mexico. And I met her many
years ago when I traveled to Mexico to
study Spanish. I went to a language
school to study Spanish, but I also took
that trip to have fun and to explore
another country. So, I stayed there for
five weeks and I met my wife at the
language school where I was studying.
She was studying English because if I
remember correctly, she was going to
take her TOEFL test, I think. And I was
studying Spanish. And at that school
they
um had this conversation class where the
locals who were learning uh English um
could talk to the foreigners who were
learning Spanish. So I was able to meet
my wife at this school and uh three
years later we got married.
So before that before we got married uh
we lived uh in different countries. I
lived in the US and she lived in Mexico
for three years. We were in a
longdistance
relationship as we call it. So that
wasn't easy, but we did it. And I
visited her many times in Mexico uh
while we were dating, meaning while we
uh were in a relationship before we were
married. and she visited me in the US as
well. And when we got married, we had
two weddings. Not uh two marriages.
I can only get married once, but we had
two wedding celebrations.
One in Mexico and one in the US. And
then after we got married, I moved to
Mexico and I had to adapt to a
completely different culture and
lifestyle.
I had to um adapt to the customs in
Mexico and the culture,
the differences in uh the culture there.
It wasn't simple. It was a little
complicated. But um the 3 years
uh prior to that, meaning before that, I
became more uh accustomed to Mexican
culture because I talked to uh my wife
every day on the phone uh and learned
more about the country. So, uh, I was
able to adapt, but it was a little hard,
of course, and my wife and I both had to
go through immigration
processes. Uh, I became a resident
uh in Mexico and my wife became a
resident here in the US. And it's not
fun to deal with immigration
processes. It's not easy to go through
those processes. Uh, but my wife did
that. For me, it was easier in Mexico.
Uh, and then we moved to the US. Now, we
live in the US and my wife has adapted
to the customs here, the culture here.
So, now it's her turn to live in a
foreign country. and adapt to the
different culture. So before we moved
here, my son was born in Mexico. So he
was born in Guadalajara
and my daughter was actually born here.
So my son was born in Mexico, but my
daughter was born in California, but now
they both have dual citizenship. This
means that they are citizens of Mexico
and citizens of the United States. So
both of them have dual citizenship
as we say. My children will both be
bilingual. My son is already bilingual.
He speaks English and Spanish, but he's
very young, so he still needs to learn a
lot. He doesn't speak uh like an adult
yet. He's still learning how to speak.
So, it's really fun to watch him learn
both languages.
He is developing
his skills in English and in Spanish.
It's really interesting to watch this
happen.
My daughter is still too young to talk.
So, she doesn't speak English or
Spanish, but she will because my wife
speaks to her in Spanish and I speak to
her in English. So, she will also be
bilingual.
My family
uh we visit Mexico
regularly.
Uh we visit Mexico every year or maybe
twice a year. So Mexico is still very
important to my family. My wife's
parents lived there and I lived there
for years, six years I think. So it's uh
a part of me.
Uh what I'm trying to say is um I have
spent a lot of time in Mexico. So it's
like my second home, right? So we visit
Mexico regularly,
but of course we live in the US. Um, and
because we live here,
we have more American customs, but also
some Mexican customs. For example, we
eat lunch
um more like um at the same time that
people in Mexico eat lunch or sometimes
even later. Um but uh that's just one
example. Uh there are other Mexican
customs that uh we also have but we live
in the US now. So most of our customs
our habits uh are more um habits and
customs from here. So, uh there are many
good things about having an
international family, but there are also
challenges. Of course, it's not the
easiest thing. Okay. However, I am very
thankful that I have my international
family. It's perfect for me and I am
very thankful for my situation, my wife,
my children, my experiences
with them and living in Mexico. So, uh,
for me it is really interesting and fun
and cool to have this international
family, but it's not for everyone. For
many people, it would be challenging to
have this type of family.
But, uh, I hope that you enjoyed this
video. Remember that if you need my
training to help you understand English
better and pronounce
words and phrases better, more like a
native speaker, then make sure to sign
up for my membership so you can get my
specialized training. Okay, that link is
down below. All right, I hope you
enjoyed this A1 listening practice
video. Maybe it was a little challenging
for you, but that's good. Watch it again
and again and again until you can
understand everything. All right, I'll
talk to you in the next